# 張凱鵬 (ZHANG, Kaipeng)

## **General Information**

I am a master student of department of Computer Science and Information Engineering, National Taiwan University supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu. Before coming to NTU, I got my B.Eng. degree in the College of Computer Science & Technology, Donghua University in June 2016. Besides, I was a research assistant at MMLAB of the Chinese University of Hong Kong at Shenzhen under the supervision of Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao. My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, deep learning, and face analysis.

Tel: (86) 18817957729 E-mail: kp\_zhang@foxmail.com

## Education

Undergraduate: in Computer Science and Information Engineering, 2016 - persent

College of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

Undergraduate: in Computer Network Engineering (The class of excellent engineer), 2013 - 2016

College of Computer Science & Technology School

Donghua University, Shanghai, China

GPA: 87/100

Undergraduate: in Electronic Information Engineering,

2012 - 2013

College of Information, Mechanical and Electronic Engineering

Shanghai Normal University, Shanghai, China

GPA: 85/100

## **Research Interests**

Computer Vision: Face analysis, face detection Recognition and Machine Learning: Deep learning

#### **Publications**

Yandong Wen, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition," *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2016 (accepted)

**Kaipeng Zhang**, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks," in *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Workshops (CVPRW)*, 2016 **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task

Cascaded Convolutional Networks," IEEE Signal Processing Letters (accepted)

# **Honors & Awards**

ChaLearn Looking at People workshop,	CVPR 2016 - Track 2	First Price (1 <sup>st</sup> winner)		2016
ChaLearn Looking at People workshop,	CVPR 2016 - Track 3	First Price (1 <sup>st</sup> winner)		2016
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis		Donghua University		2016
China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling		Second Prize	Shanghai	2015
Wuyi Mathematical Contest	Third Prize	Jiangsu Provin	ce	2015
MathorCup & CAA Worldwide Mathematical Contest		Winner Price	China	2015
China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling		Third Prize	Shanghai	2014
Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Third Prize	Donghua Univ	ersity	2014
ACM-ICPC Contest on Campus	Third Prize	Donghua Univ	ersity	2014

Second Prize Scholarship		Shanghai Normal University	2013
Mathematical Contest in Modeling	Second Prize	Shanghai Normal University	2012

## <u>Internship</u>

Shenzhen institutes of advanced technology, Chinese academy of sciences, visiting student

2015.07 - 2016.08

# **Research Experience**

#### Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks

2016.03

- Propose a multi-task and general-to-specific fine-tuning scheme that exploits the inherent correlation between face identity, gender, smile and other face attributes
- Propose a tasks-aware face cropping scheme
- This work has been accepted by CVPRW 2016 and win the First Price of ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge (Track 2).

## Face recognition using discriminative deep feature learning approach

2016.02 - 2016.03

- Joint supervision of softmax loss and center loss (designed by us) to obtain the deep features with the two key learning objectives, inter-class dispersion and intra-class compactness as much as possible
- Achieves the state-of-the-art results on MegaFace (Small Training Set) and competitive results on LFW and YTF
- This work has been accepted by ECCV 2016

## Face detection and alignment by deep learning

2015.07 - 2016.01

- Joint face and facial landmark detection using cascaded CNNs framework.
- Achieves the state-of-the-art performance in FDDB, WIDER FACE benchmark for face detection and AFLW benchmark for face alignment in high running speed.
- This work has been accepted by IEEE Signal Processing Letters

## **Project Experience**

# Useless commodity comment classification

2015.05

- Build comment vector model (Use jieba Chinese word segmentation module, TF-IDF formula, stacked autoencoder)
- Useless comment classification (Use random forest and K-means for labeled and none labeled data situation)

# Microblog user modeling and public opinion analysis

2014.12 - 2016.05

- Build a user model based on ontology (Use TF-IDF formula, Baidu baike as ontology)
- Topic and public opinion analysis (Use LDA topic model and random forest for public opinion classification)

## The application of face recognition in video retrieval

2014.09 - 2014.11

- Use Eigenface for face recognition and retrieve video by personal identity
- The system runs on Hadoop for large-scale data processing

# **English & Professional Skill**

English: CET4 (529)

Senior Network Engineer (approved and authorized by the Ministry of Human Resources an Social Security, China)

EMC Academic Associate, Information Storage and Management

EMC Academic Associate, Cloud Infrastructure and Services

C/C++, Python, and Matlab programming